Glen Harding

Email: Glen.Harding.nz@gmail.com, Mobile: 02102972471, Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/glen-harding-5a1317114,

GitHub: https://github.com/nelg62, Portfolio: https://nelg62.github.io/

CAREER SUMMARY

I am detail-oriented and a motivated software engineer with 5+ years of experience in IT. Good at fixing and supplying technical help to end-users no matter where they are. Recently, I earned a Professional Certificate in Software Engineering from AUT. I learned how to design and implement software. I want to start a developer career with the good knowledge of end users, mindset to grow, and a steady commitment to learning.

KEY SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS
- Frameworks and Libraries: React, Next.js, Node.is, Express
- Database Management: MongoDB, MySQL, Redis
- API Development: RESTful APIs, API Integration

- Version Control: Git,
- Cloud Technologies: Familiarity with Azure or AWS
- Technical Support and Troubleshooting: Diagnosing and resolving technical issues
- **Problem-Solving Skills**: Critical thinking and analytical skills

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2024 - 2024

AUT/Institute of Data

Software Bootcamp - Professional Certificate in Software Engineering

- Software Development Principles
- API Development and Integration
- Javascript Programming
- Front End Development
- Back End and Full Stack Development
- Interactive Web Design
- Web Design with React II

Project Learning (Can find on Portfolio Website)

- 3X Mini Projects
- Capstone Project

2017 - 2017

Techtorium NZ Institute of Info Tech

Level 7 Diploma in Cloud Management in Information Technology

- Install, upgrade, migrate, configure & troubleshoot Windows Client OS
- Configure & install DNS, WINS, DHCP, network infrastructure & servers
- Configure Active Directory in Windows Server Identify, protect, authenticate & asses network security & basic Cryptography
- Use MDT & SCCM for Deployment

2016 - 2016

Techtorium NZ Institute of Info Tech

Level 6 Diploma in Networking and Security in Information Technology

- WDS, MDT Deployment
- Installing and Configuring Windows Server 2012
- Administering Windows Server 2012
- Configuring Advanced Windows Server 2012 Services

2015 - 2015

Techtorium NZ Institute of Info Tech

Level 5 Diploma in PC Support in Information Technology

- PC Hardware & Software Installation, Repair & Support
- Networking Concepts and Server Administration
- Internet & Networking Security, WAN & LAN Security
- Windows Applications, Operating Systems, and Web-Creation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Foundation Partners Limited May 2023 - 2024

Level 1 & Level 2 Service Desk Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Provide first and second level ICT support to customers at medium to large businesses
 - o Predominantly via phone assistance
 - Occasional on-site visits as required
- Collaborate with other team members to deliver support services
- Assist clients as needed with various ICT issues
- Follow directives from Senior Engineers or Senior Managers for on-site assistance
 - Diagnose ICT issues on-site
- Communicate proactively with end-users and directing engineer/manager
 - Update status of projects or requests to end-users and supervisors
- Proficient in utilizing various software solutions to troubleshoot and resolve issues effectively:
 - 3cx
 - TeamViewer
 - N-central
 - Halopsa

Fusion Tech Limited June 2019 - May 2023

ICT Support Technician

Responsibilities:

- Troubleshoot IT issues for small to medium-sized businesses, including server management.
- Set up mobile phones, laptops, and other devices.
- Proficient with software and tools such as Office 365, Sophos routers, and Acronis.
- Knowledgeable in:
 - Azure
 - Sharepoint
 - Nagios
 - Shadowprotect
 - Scalefusion
 - Eset
 - Yealink PBX and phone systems.
- Work on a helpdesk, including using a ticketing system and taking phone calls.
- Provide on-site IT support
- Work independently and as part of a team.
- Willing to learn new technologies and software to stay up-to-date with industry advancements.
- Use Active Directory to create and manage users and groups.

Darkwing Corporation Limited June 2018 - June 2019

ICT Support Technician

Responsibilities:

- Provide on-site IT support for small to medium-sized businesses and individual clients.
- Troubleshoot IT-related issues for both Mac and iPhone-based devices.
- Fix hardware and software issues for Mac devices.

- Use backup and cloning tools such as Time Machine and Shadow Protect.
- Set up Android and iPhone phones, as well as Mac laptops.
- Install OS and recover lost data.
- Understand how companies and individuals use their devices and troubleshoot issues accordingly.
- Work independently and as part of a team.
- Learn new technologies and software to stay up-to-date with industry advancements.

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

I've always found technology to be interesting. Whether it is a device or a software program, I feel excited when I see new things as I like to test it out to see how it works. Learning programming has opened me up to many new possibilities for developing and accomplishing things I always wanted to. Going into programming has not only expanded my horizons but also given me the tools to innovate and bring my ideas to life. I would like to work towards a Career in DevOps and or Platform Engineering.